Finn Thompson

www.finnthompson.me in linkedin.com/in/nnifinn

nnifinn@gmail.com J (530)-414-4849 Seattle, WA

I am a full stack software developer with a passion for delivering excellent software solutions. I have programmed extracurricularly for 8+ years while cultivating a user-focused mentality through my education.

Skills

Programming: Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Regex, React, Jest, SQL, Chrome extensions
Technologies: Git, Markdown, VSCode, IntelliJ, Windows, Ubuntu, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Figma
Holistic Skills: UX design, Agile, English/technical writing, teamwork and communication

Online Activity: Stack Overflow (23k+ reputation), GitHub (15+ repositories)

Projects

Netflix Controller Chrome Extension

JavaScript, UI/UX

• Chrome extension providing an intuitive interface for controlling Netflix with a gamepad

Various JavaScript Libraries, Published with Documentation

JavaScript, Tech Writing

- FormPersistence.js persist form data across page refreshes (featured in JavaScript Weekly)
- Gamepads.js add enhanced HTML5 gamepad support including button events and icons
- Pseudo:styler toggle CSS pseudo class styles on elements (co-developer)

Smart Prescription Management Device (Team Capstone)

Python, UI/UX, Research

- Designed, developed, and assembled Arduino and Raspberry Pi prototypes
- Developed C and Python code to power the device and its touchscreen UI
- Led a usability research study to evaluate the first iteration of the prototype

UW Course Seat Claimer

Java, UI/UX

• Java GUI application that listens to a user's email inbox for open seat notifications on full classes and registers the user for the open seat, dropping conflicted courses if specified

Education

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

B.S. in Human Centered Design and Engineering

Sept. 2014 - June 2018

- GPA: 3.65 overall, 3.8 in major
- Includes Computer Programming II, Web Programming, Physical Computing, Interactive Systems Design

Experience

Shift Supervisor, Starbucks

Seattle, WA

• Empowered a team of baristas to deliver exceptional customer experiences

Oct. 2016 - Dec. 2018

• Sustained customer ratings as one of the top stores in its district

Research Intern, Scripps Translational Science Institute

La Jolla, CA

Developed a Java GUI application to save researchers time identifying gene relationships

May

May 2014 - June 2014

• Designed a term frequency-inverse document frequency algorithm to rank results

Developer / Project Lead, RuneDream

Reno. NV

Designed and developed a Java application to automate gameplay of the game RuneScape
 Jan. 2012 - May 2013

• Created a website, forum, and API to deliver and support the application with 50k+ downloads